# Scott R. Emmons

4952 NORTH SAINT PATRICKS COURT • BLOOMINGTON, IN • 47404 PHONE: 812.606.7839 (C) • EMAIL: SCOTT@SCOTTEMMONS.COM • WEBSITE: SCOTTEMMONS.COM

## **Professional Profile**

I have experience in business and computer science in academia and industry. I have been interning at an informatics research lab specializing in data visualization for the past two years, a capacity in which I'm conducting data analysis research. I also founded a marketing consulting firm and have been working with local businesses to grow their companies through strategic decisions such as brand definition and through technical implementation such as web design. I bring creative insight, experience, and initiative to problems in business and computer science.

## **Education**

Bloomington High School North, 2011 – Present

- -- Anticipated graduation: May 2015 (Honors diploma)
- -- Cumulative GPA of 4.31 / 4.0
- -- Honors & AP Coursework
  - Physics AP
  - Calculus AP
  - English 12 AP
  - Microeconomics AP
  - Latin AP
  - US History AP
  - English 11 AP
  - Latin III Honors
  - Precalculus and Trigonometry Honors
  - Physics Honors
  - Algebra II Honors
  - Chemistry Honors
  - English 10 Honors
  - Geography and History of the World Honors
  - Geometry Honors
  - Biology Honors
  - English 9 Honors
  - Introduction to Social Sciences Honors

## Online Coursework

- -- Introduction to Computer Science and Programming, MIT OpenCourseWare
- -- Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs, MIT OpenCourseWare
- -- Information Visualization, Cyberinfrastructure for Network Science Center
- -- Game Theory, Stanford University and the University of British Columbia
- -- Principles of Economics, Stanford Online

# **Work Experience**

Sparq Creative Solutions, December 2013 – Present

- -- Cofounder and owner of marketing consulting firm
- -- Created brand identity, logo, and website for Spencer Psychology
- -- Designed website for Fearless Performance, LLC
- -- Keep the internal books, file taxes, and code company website

Cyberinfrastructure for Network Science Center, Indiana University, Sept. 2013 – Present

- -- Learning, teaching, and researching with data visualization tools
- -- Collaborating on an international research project to map scientific publication
- -- Collaborating on research project analyzing MOOC datasets
- -- Leading independent research project to map consumer purchasing behavior
- -- Taught 2014 and 2015 Information Visualization MOOCs as Student Liaison
- -- Reviewed book Visual Insights: A Practical Guide to Making Sense of Data
- -- Created a geospatial map of the showings of the short film "Humanexus"

Volunteers in Medicine of Monroe County, March 2013 – July 2013

-- Created and analyzed custom database searches for patient records

Oliver Winery, June – August 2012

-- Created pivot-table reports in Excel for sales analysis

## **Extracurricular Activities**

- -- Founder, BHSN Life Skills Academy, 2013 Present
- -- Vice President, Habitat for Humanity, 2011 Present
- -- Business Professionals of America, 2011 2014
- -- Cougar Leader, 2013 2014
- -- Track, 2012
- -- Cross Country, 2011 2012
- -- Jazz & Pep Band Drummer, 2011 2012
- -- National Honor Society
- -- Latin Honor Society
- -- WTHR Brain Game
- -- Academic Super Bowl

# **Community Activities**

- -- Hoosier Hills Food Bank, 2006 Present
- -- Interfaith Winter Shelter, 2010 Present
- -- Volunteers in Medicine, 2013 2014
- -- Milwaukee Mission Trip, 2014
- -- Detroit Mission Trip, 2013
- -- New Orleans Mission Trip, 2012
- -- Nashville Mission Trip, 2011
- -- Childcare Worker, First United Methodist Church 2012 2014

# **Conferences & Talks**

- -- CNS Open House Speaker, November 2013, November 2014
- -- Web Science Conference Participant, June 2014
- -- Lugar Symposium Representative, December 2013
- -- Plug-and-Play Macroscopes Workshop Participant, November 2013

# **Press Coverage**

- -- "Bloomington North team enjoys challenge of 'Brain Game'", Herald Times.
- -- "Interactive open house shows SOIC tools", <u>Indiana Daily Student.</u>

# **Honors & Awards**

### Academic

- -- National Merit Scholarship Finalist
- -- Eight-time Student of the Year at Bloomington High School North
  - AP US History
  - Honors Physics
  - Honors Algebra II
  - Honors Chemistry
  - Honors English 10
  - Honors Geography and History of the World
  - Honors Geometry
  - Honors Biology
- -- M<sup>3</sup> Math Modelling Challenge Honorable Mention Paper, 2015
- -- Honor Roll

#### Athletic

- -- Varsity Letter, Cross Country, 2011, 2012
- -- Varsity Letter, Track, 2012
- -- Most Improved Athlete, Track, 2012

## Music

-- Outstanding Drums, Sursa Hall, Ball State Jazz Festival, 2012

### **Business Professionals of America**

- -- 4<sup>th</sup> place, National Competition, Small Business Management, 2013
- -- 10<sup>th</sup> place, National Competition, Computer Programming Concepts, 2013
- -- 1<sup>st</sup> place, State Competition, Financial Math and Analysis, 2014
- -- 1<sup>st</sup> place, State Competition, Small Business Management, 2014
- -- 1<sup>st</sup> place, State Competition, Financial Math and Analysis, 2013
- -- 1<sup>st</sup> place, State Competition, Small Business Management, 2013
- -- 6<sup>th</sup> place, State Competition, Advanced Interview Skills, 2014
- -- 6<sup>th</sup> place, State Competition, Computer Programming Concepts, 2013
- -- 8<sup>th</sup> place, State Competition, Computer Programming Concepts, 2014
- -- 6<sup>th</sup> place, State Competition, Interview Skills, 2013
- -- 1<sup>st</sup> place, District Competition, Fundamental Spreadsheet Applications, 2012